uh recently somebody made a comment I in
my neim apology video I made a comment
about um neim wrongly and I was wrong
again uh wrongly using the state
directory and and somebody in the
comments uh you know sort of patiently
said you know that's xtg thing now and I
was like no I didn't know that and so I
looked into it and it turns out that go
which is one of the ways that I know
about this because there's there's
there's user cacher user config user
Homer but there's no user Stater so I
went ahead and did a search and found uh
that issue um 68
988 on the go project itself is because
I was getting ready to make a PR to add
user State there and I went ahead and
did a search and I found that and and so
and then I wanted to go ahead and view
this uh to see this so let's just look
at this really quickly um so the go
project is considering adding it and
there they were noting there's go
actually added Telemetry um a while ago
it's a huge debate uh about whether did
we got a lot of bad press about adding
Telemetry data and this particular issue
um is related to the Telemetry data
being in the wrong place and so I'm
going to go ahead and read it it says my
ex config go Telemetry directory uh
config go Telemetry is now full of data
files in violation of xtg based
directory specification blah which
reserves XG home for
configuration uh what did you expect to
see I expected to see Telemetry data and
XG stayed home instead and then there's
a several very instructive comments
these are relatively recent August is
pretty recent those from the meeting on
this issue so this is cool the go team
knows about this they've already added
it and there's a good chance that we're
going to see a user State dur os.
userstate dur at some point there hasn't
been a PR committed or even considered
for this as far as I know um but I think
this is going to be an important point
now this particular thread is about what
to do with the Telemetry data and where
to put it so maybe the CB still be open
to a PR that just adds um you know user
State you home which I which I hope I
really hope they do add um and so here
let's go ahead and look at it someone
point out that unfortunately it seems to
me that we are we are not the only
offenders searching my config finds
plenty of data files of various
applications nevertheless we'd like to
be good citizens changing this now would
be non-trivial disruptive for example
all our documentation historically talks
about this this tempature data being
stale um there advantage of it being in
user config blah blah blah we're not
sure whether it's desirable to separate
or not so so this the answer here is it
doesn't look like there's a PR to add
user Stater I am going to attempt myself
to submit a go PR to the project which
adds user State dur so we can get that
in 123 or whatever version we're on I
personally would love to have that had
it and it's Ultra trivial uh to write
the code to look that up so I think that
that that function could be safely added
to the go project whether or not they
decide to put Telemetry in there at all
so I just wanted to say that so again
another apology to the person it turns
out that neovim is ahead of the game uh
on this particular issue as this
Telemetry team has noted that not very
many people are doing this and many most
of us don't know about it so I'm making
a video so you know so xdg Stater us
user State dur is a thing bye